Today I'm going over the 18 core Codeex
concepts that you actually need to know
in order to start using it right away
and getting value from it. It doesn't
matter if you're not technical at all or
you've never used Codex before. By the
end of this video, you'll understand
exactly how this thing actually works so
that you can start using it right away.
So, let's not waste any time and just
get straight into this one. All right,
so I've split these 18 core concepts
into four different parts and they get
cooler as we continue to go on. So, part
one, we're going to start off here is
foundations. So, we're going to kick off
with concept number one, which is
projects. Now, a lot of you guys, I'm
assuming, have used chatgbt or claude in
the web before where you can talk to an
LLM and it can, you know, give you an
answer. But the problem you face is that
every time you're talking to it or you
start a new chat, you have to kind of
familiarize it with you and your
business and what you're working on that
week or that quarter. So, with projects,
you can basically keep everything
organized into one project so that as
you keep working inside of it, it only
gets smarter about knowing who you are.
So, right here on the lefth hand side,
you can see that I've got a few projects
going on. I've got Herk 2, I've got
Hyperframes, I've got Trading Challenge,
I've got AIS demo, and I typically am
always just working inside of my Herk 2
project. My Herk 2 project is basically
what I call my AI operating system. And
what a project is is actually very
simple. It is just a collection of
folders and files. So right here, this
is inside of my file explorer on my
computer and it's called Herk 2. And
this is exactly the project that I have
open in Codeex. When I say right here,
I'm inside of Codex, right? This is the
file path that I'm working in, which is
if I open this up, my Herk 2 project. So
what that means is this project has
rules about me. It has, you know,
credentials. It has all my projects. It
has all my YouTube videos. This thing
has so much knowledge about me. So now
when I come into the chat and I say,
"Hey, can you just give me a rundown of
what we've been working on this past
month?" This thing basically gets
familiarized with my project and then it
looks at everything that we've been
working on together. It even looks
through all of my previous chats that
I've had with Codeex. So here you can
see that it looked back from the past
month and it said, "Here's what we've
worked on. We've been improving your
Herk 2 and your AISOS. We've been
working on YouTube content and strategy,
AI model testing and demos, apps and
product experiments, websites, branding,
business operations. So, this is no
longer just an AI chatbot. This is now a
co-founder. This is a personal
assistant, which brings us on really
nicely into concept number two, which is
something called an agents.md.
And don't let that MD intimidate you
here. If I go over to the right hand
side and I open up my files, you'll
notice if I scroll down, I have
something right here called an
agents.mmd. And when I open this up,
it's literally just a markdown file.
That's what the MD means. And it's just
rules. Like this is a very simple thing
that you all can read and it's not
technical at all. So this is basically
like the rules for your project. So you
remember inside of my Herk 2 project, I
have this agents onMD. Well, if I was
inside of my Hyperframes editor project,
there would be a different agents.m MD.
So this thing basically just sets the
ground rules for the project that you're
working in. So right here you can see
that this one says, "Hey, you are Nate
Herk's AI operating system. Your job is
to help him spend less time on
operations so he can focus on making
YouTube videos." And then I give it
things like core operating rules for how
to work with me. I give it some stuff
about how to be safe on my desktop. And
then the real bulk of my agent MD is
what I call routing. So this is a
routing map. It basically means, okay,
so yeah, Nate's project is huge. There
are hundreds, probably thousands of
files and folders inside of this
project. So let me just explain to you
how this actually works. If you need
business stuff, you go to the wiki. If
you need corporate structure, you go to
the corporate structure section inside
the wiki. If you need his voice, you go
here. If you need course knowledge, you
go here. If you want active projects,
you go here. So everything that I'm
doing, we're routing it back somewhere
so that my agents.mmd file tells this
project where everything is so that
every time I open up a new chat, like I
said, I don't have to reexplain things.
And basically the way that this works,
if we picture this being a chat thread,
you know, you come over here and you
say, "Hey, you say, "Hey, Codex, I need
you to help me do this." And before
Codex actually even like reads this
message, what it does is it first reads
the agents.mmd. So I'm just going to put
a here and that stands for agents.mmd.
But codeex will basically read this and
then it will read your message and then
it will respond with something like, you
know, hey, how can I help you today? So
the kind of stuff that you want to put
inside your agents.mmd is the type of
stuff that you want codeex to know about
you every single time you're talking to
it in that project. And now moving on to
concept number three, we have something
called the agent loop. So you'll hear
about something like codecs or claude
code or Hermes agent. These are all
called agent harnesses. And these
harnesses have their own agent loops.
And real quick, if you're wondering
about codecs versus like work, chatbt
work, I always use codecs. The majority
of my work is not building products or
building software, but I only use codecs
because it's just the most powerful. And
once you get through this video, you'll
realize how easy it is to use. But
anyways, the reason why this is called a
harness is because they have this thing
called the agentic loop, which at the
highest level basically just means when
you ask the agent a question, it has a
bunch of tools at its disposal and it
basically thinks and it reasons and it
uses tools and then it responds to you
and then it thinks and then it reasons
and it takes action. It uses tools,
responds to you and that's basically the
agent loop. And what's really awesome
about that is you can see it in action.
So right here you can see that this said
worked for 25 seconds. And if I open
this up, we can basically see what it
did, right? So like it hid this response
and it gave us our output, but it had a
reasoning loop inside. It first said,
"Okay, I'll check our recent tasks and
project nodes, then I'll pull together
the main themes from the past month."
And when it did that, it ran all these
commands. It ran this, which you don't
have to know what this means, but
basically what this did is it looked
inside something right here called a
memory.md. So very similar to the
agents.md, but this is about memories
rather than just like rules. It then
looked at other chats. And so we can
basically watch it do things. So, to
show you guys a real example of this,
hey, could you just check my most recent
YouTube video that I uploaded and give
me three comments that you thought were
funny from that video.
Now, as I shoot this off, what I want
you guys to pay attention to is what
we're watching. So, first it said
thinking. Now, it says, "I'll find your
latest upload, read through the
comments, and pick three that made me
laugh." And now we can see what it's
doing. So, it's looking through the
memory. It's looking at these things.
It's running these commands. And these
commands are basically right here. It's
reading, you know, files to get
established and to get oriented with
what it needs to do. And so, you can
actually learn a lot about how codeex
works and how to best work with it by
when you ask it a question, you just
kind of watch what it does. So, you can
see what it had to do was it had to run
a command in order to actually go talk
to YouTube, look at the data, and pull
it back. And now we can see three
comments. We have this one, never seen
anyone so excited to lose money. Trading
with AI is very easy. I just prompt
Claude only take profitable trades. And
if I want to lose money, I can do it
myself faster and better. And what
you'll notice is how quick that all
happened. Now, I do have my Astra on
fast mode, but I will talk about that
later because that is a core concept
that's coming up. All right, and moving
on to the last concept of part one. It's
a slashgoal. And this is honestly one of
my favorite things about AI ever. It's
the ability to do something called a
slash goal. And right here, you can see
that that says set a goal to keep
pursuing. Now, AI agents are super goal
oriented, which is super cool. So, let's
say you have Mr. AI agent right here and
you basically say, "Hey, here is your
goal. You know, this is what you need to
do." And you give it this objective
goal. What happens is it will basically
just keep working and keep working and
keep working until it actually hits that
goal. And it's cool because even if you
kind of like give them a roadblock, they
are going to be so goal-oriented that
they're going to keep retrying different
things and they're going to just
basically keep going until they're able
to succeed and hit that goal for you.
Now, obviously, the more objective a
goal, the easier it is to prove that.
So, if you say, "Hey, can you, you know,
work on this until you've pulled in 257
sources and then write the report."
That's an objective goal, right? 257
sources and written report. But you can
also set goals that are a little bit
more emotional. Like your goal could
maybe be more like, you know, until
you're fully satisfied or until you've,
you know, verified this over and over
and you feel good about it. And in that
case, you're still going to, you know,
get there and it will still decide when
it's done. But as you get more objective
with your goal, the goal prompts are
just more effective. But let me show you
one goal that I actually did that you
guys have already been witnessing in
this specific example is I went to my
hyperframes project. And hyperframes
basically lets your coding agents build
HTML and then render it as video. So
essentially it creates video. But what I
did here is I shot it off a/goal prompt.
You can see this one says sent as goal.
So basically what I did is I said I need
you to help me create some motion
graphics for a YouTube video. So all the
motion graphics you've seen so far were
from this exact prompt right here. I'm
going over 18 different Codex concepts.
I want, you know, an intro. I want
transition cards. I want all this. So, I
basically defined that I wanted one
intro scene and that I wanted 18 cards.
And then you can see that it said I
finished and I visually checked, meaning
it actually took screenshots to make
sure everything looked good before it
decided to be done. And now we have all
these animations. But what's cool about
the goal prompts is that models nowadays
are getting so good, the AI models are
getting so good that it's actually
better to give them a goal and then step
out of their way. If you really just try
to like micromanage them, you're kind of
just like muzzling their capabilities.
So, if the situation isn't super super
risky, give them a goal and you can get
out of the way. Now, there's one quick
thing that I felt the need to address,
which is basically the question, "But
Nate, what if we've been using cloud
code for a long time?" Well, I'm really
glad that you asked. It's actually
really simple. Really, the main
difference is the agents.mmd, thecodex,
and the aagents. Because in cloud code,
you basically have like your claw.md and
you have yourclaw. So when I first
started switching over from cla code to
codeex. All I did was I said, "Hey
codeex, take a look at this herku
project, I've been building this up
using claude code for the past couple
months. I need you to help me get this
codeex ready." And basically what that
means is I made a copy of my claw.md and
called it agents.mmd.d. So I have two of
those now. One one agents.mmd one
claude, but they're basically the same
file. And then I made a copy of all my
claude skills and put them in the agents
folder. And I made a copy of all of my
like claude settings files and I put
them in my agents. And the cool thing is
you don't have to do any of that
manually. You'd literally just say,
"Hey, Codeex, look at the documentation,
analyze my project, and make this codeex
accessible. Make it codec ready." So,
anyways, if you were feeling a little
bit of doubt about all that kind of
stuff, that's the way I did it. And now
you have a bunch of local files and
folders that you can use on any agent
harness whenever. It's very flexible.
It's very tool agnostic, and that's what
you want to be building at the end of
the day. So, anyways, had to address
that real quick. Let's get back to the
video. All right. Awesome. So, let's
move on to part two of these core
concepts, which is environments. So the
first piece of environments is number
five, which is local versus cloud. So
there's a couple things to talk about
here. The first thing is if someone
says, "Oh, is this running locally or
are these local files?" All that means
is does that exist only on the machine
that you're currently using? Whether
you're on a MacBook right now or you're
on a desktop PC like I am right now.
When you say local, it just means it's
only accessible by you. So right here,
if I open up my files, these are
basically local files. Now, they're
syncing with one drive when I want them
to. So that would kind of push them into
the cloud, but otherwise it's completely
local. So like if you're working on a
Word doc on your computer and you forgot
to save it and then email it to yourself
on so you could work on it on a
different laptop, that was a problem
because it was locally on that other
machine. But something like Google Drive
is always in the cloud obviously. But
this also goes beyond just files. This
goes to like things that are produced.
So right here you can see that it
actually created me this little site for
all these motion graphics. So if I open
up this site, you can see that I can
view all of these videos. I can click
into the different ones and it threw
this together for me really nice and it
served this to me on a local host. So
right here you can see that this URL is
127.0.0.1
and the port of this local host is 8008.
Now realistically that's not super
important. You don't really need to
understand what exactly this means. But
this is just a local host. But this is a
little confusing because it looks like
this is a web address that if I, you
know, emailed to you, you could open
this up and have the site. But what
would happen is this would show on your
screen or it would show on your computer
as nothing actually lives here. So like
if I copied this and I pasted this into
a new browser but I changed the number
to 7. I don't think I have anything
running on port 8087
on my local machine even though you
might. So nothing actually loads up. And
it's quite funny. I remember seeing
these these tweets where I think it was
a joke but it was like uh someone was
pretending they were a beginner and they
were like wow cloud code and codeex it's
so cool. Look what I built in one day.
and then they, you know, attached a
bunch of local host addresses and
obviously no one else could open that up
because they're not on that local
device. So anyways, that is the
difference between local and cloud. Now,
the other piece here is that when you're
spinning up these new chats, you can
kind of have these be either local,
meaning right here, you know, I'm
working in my local files and folders.
And that's great because codeex can
actually like edit these files, right?
It can delete things, it can make new
ones, it can edit them, it can move them
around, it can go to my downloads, it
can go to my desktop, it can do anything
on my computer really. or you could
actually have these work in the cloud.
And what you'll notice here is when you
choose cloud, you no longer have the
ability down here to actually choose the
model you were using and the permissions
because this sets up sort of like a
cloud sandbox environment. Now, I'll be
honest, I hardly ever do this because
when I'm working locally, as long as I
keep my machine on, as long as I keep my
PC on, it feels pretty cloudlike. And
here's what I mean by that. Right here,
you can see that I'm mirroring my phone
and I'm in the Chat GBT app. And if I go
over here and I click on this right
here, which says remote, this lets me
see all of my actual codeex chats that
are right here. So if I go to Herk 2 and
I go to summarize past month, this is
exactly what we were just looking at
right here. You can see this is
literally the same conversation. It has
those three chats and I could come in
here and I could say hi. And this gets
sent in my actual codeex right here on
my laptop or sorry on my desktop as well
as my phone. So, as long as my machine's
on, even though this is running locally
and I'm out on a walk, I'm out at
dinner, I could even be in a different
state and I could control my desktop
from my phone right here. So, let's say
for some reason I left a file locally on
my computer, I could just say, "Hey, can
you email that file to me?" And then I
could use it on my laptop. So, anyways,
just wanted to show off that remote
capability. And that's going to bring us
into concept number six, which is work
trees. Now, honestly, this is something
where if you're not really building
software or, you know, production apps,
this isn't going to matter to you too
much. Like I don't hardly ever use work
trees, but it is good to know about
since you will see these in the
interface. So right here you can see
that if I was to go to um the local
setting, it says that you can work in a
new local work tree which says create a
copy of Herk 2 to work in parallel. So
basically because I'm working in Herk 2,
if I was going to do something like
risky or if I wanted to try and
experiment with something or for
example, if I was building software and
I wanted to try to change the way that
the onboarding flow worked, but I wanted
to like not interrupt the main branch,
especially if other people on my team
are working on that main branch, I could
use a work tree to basically create a
copy and I could test in there. And then
what you can do later is you can merge
it back into the main. So it's basically
just a duplicate that lets you test. But
like I said, there's hardly any times
for knowledge work that I ever use work
trees. And if I ever am building
software and stuff, a lot of times Codex
will say, "Hey, by the way, you might
want to use this. You might want to do
this in a new work tree." So, I wanted
to call it out because it's important
because you might see things like this
master branch and you might see other
work trees that might have been spun up
automatically. But, I will say it's not
something that I'm actively thinking
about or think that you need to be
actively thinking about in order to get
the most out of codeex. So, wanted to
bring that up. But, let's move on to
number seven, which iscodeex.
Now, this is really interesting. We
talked about how when you're inside of
your project, you have things like an
agents.mmd. Now, if I go to my files,
there's also something in here called a
codeex. So, if I open this up, what
you'll see in here is I have some agents
and I have some workflows, but I also
have a config. ML file, which is
basically like some local settings. And
there are basically going to be two
different places where a codex file
lives. And that's either going to be
inside of your project. So like in this
example, this is my codeex inside of my
Herk 2. But there's also going to be one
which is user or global, which means
this lives under your actual user. And
these are settings that hold things like
memories and sessions and automations.
These are things that will apply to your
global codeex. So whenever you're in
codeex, regardless of what your project
you're actually in, the docex will have
personal settings and app data and stuff
like that. Now once again, I think this
is something it's important to
understand where that lives and what it
does. But this isn't a folder that I'm
actively thinking about and actively
having to like maintain. But I did want
to call that out because sometimes if
you need to have a certain setting
applied or something like that, that is
where it lives. Now, the cool thing
about this is if you're ever confused,
you say, "Hey Codeex, what did you do
there?" Or, "Do we need to add this to
mycodex or do we need to move this to a
different folder?" You can just ask it
questions because it can search through
its own documentation and understand how
to do things like correctly. But I do
think that understanding the difference
between project scope things and user
scope things that's definitely important
especially as we get into the agents
which is going to come up later. And
that is a great segue into part three of
the core concepts which is control and
customization. So number eight here is
about different AI models. So when you
are starting a new chat you can choose
the model you want to use. You can also
change the model in between messages.
So, I could shoot off a message on Astra
and then I could, you know, change this
to something else and then I could shoot
off another message and I can keep
changing if I want. Now, if you're
watching this video way later, maybe the
model names look different, but
essentially the theory is the same. You
have different models to choose from and
they all have different prices and
strengths. So, like right now, GBD6
Astra is just the absolute strongest,
but it's going to cost the most. It's
going to eat the most of your weekly
limit. Right here, you can see that I'm
at 100% because it just got reset. But
as you chat with Astra, it will drain
your weekly usage faster than you know
5.6 Soul would, which would drain your
usage limit faster than 5.6 Tarot would.
Now, right here, I just want you to look
at the API pricing so I can explain to
you how these models are actually
billing you. So, they build by tokens,
and they usually build by 1 million
tokens. Meaning, on Astra, for every 1
million input tokens, it will cost you
$10. And for every 1 million output
tokens, it will cost you 50 bucks. And
here you can see the different pricing
for these different models. And you can
see how it gets cheaper as you go down.
Now, this is API pricing, which means if
you were building an automation that was
programmatically using these models,
that's how much it would cost you. But
this usage inside of Codex, that's not
programmatic. This is usage limit or
subscription limit. So, when you pay 20
or 100 or 200 bucks a month for Codeex,
this is what you're actually your usage
limit is eating up is that subscription.
And you're getting way more inference.
Like, this is a $200 a month
subscription. And if I use all of my
weekly usage every single week, I'm
getting about $14,000 worth of inference
every month and I'm only paying 200
bucks for that. So the subscriptions are
much cheaper than if you were using the
API pricing. But if you ever do go over
your weekly limit, you'd have to buy
extra codeex credits. I don't exactly
know why they price it like this, but
you know, you can see they just give you
codeex credits instead. So let's say I
went over my weekly limit. I could go
here and I could click on buy credits.
This would bring up this screen which
lets you buy credits by like the
thousands or something like that. And
that is what I wanted to show you guys.
So like 2500 credits, 5,000 credits,
25,000 credits. And this is how it would
charge you based on those tokens. Now,
if you've never heard of tokens before,
I know that might be a little confusing.
Think about it as roughly four
characters or roughly 3/4s of a word.
And there's an OpenAI tokenizer right
here where if I paste in some text, it
will show you how many tokens this would
be. So this paragraph for example was
about 240 characters or sorry 274
characters and about 56 tokens. And it's
interesting because sometimes
punctuation is a token, right? Like this
period is a token, this comma is a
token, this word's a token, um this
word's a token. And this is basically
just kind of breaking down what it might
look like for these tokens. But anyways,
you can see this was 56. And what else
you might notice is that I earlier said
input tokens or output tokens. Input
tokens are whatever you're feeding in.
So your prompts or if it's reading like
a PDF or a word doc those are input
because they're going into the model and
output tokens are anything that it
outputs. So even its reasoning here is
output tokens. This entire thread is
output tokens and that's why the output
tokens are more expensive. Okay. So
let's move on to number nine which is
about effort. So within each model not
only do you choose the model but you can
also choose the effort level. So right
here I can move Astra down to medium or
I can move it down to low or I can move
it up to extra high or if I go like
ultra I have to allow full access
because that can get you know pretty
autonomous. But anyways the point being
as you move up on these effort levels
you get more quality like you get more
intelligence but you also get more cost.
It's more expensive to run it at higher
effort levels. And that's why when you
see these benchmarks, when there are new
models released, you'll see the model,
like for example, Cloud Fable 5, you can
see this mark was on low and this one
was on medium and this one was on high.
So, it shows how one model can behave
differently and also cost a different
amount based on the effort level that it
was being used and tested at. Now, it
actually is pretty nice to play with
these because sometimes Astra High is
just so much more powerful than what you
need to do. Like if you were using GBD6
Astra High to help you write an email,
that's overkill and you're paying way
more than you should realistically to
write an email. I could probably come
down here and use 56 Terra and be just
fine with that and it's a lot cheaper.
So definitely try to play with the model
and play with the effort based on your
task. But a lot of times if you're just
doing a lot of knowledge work, I would
just chuck it on sole and I'd maybe just
go to medium and just call it a day
there. Now the other thing about effort
is you can do something called fast
mode. This obviously makes the model
respond quicker and do things quicker.
And it it's 1.5 speed, but it costs you
more usage, so it will eat your weekly
subscription faster as well. All right,
and moving on to number 10, we have
permissions. Basically, right down here,
you can see that this is orange and it
says full access. This is basically
Codeex's yolo mode, which means that
it's not going to stop and ask you a
bunch of permissions and questions. Can
I do this? Can I do this? If you go on
ask for approval, it's going to always
ask to edit external files and always
ask to use the internet. So that's if
you want to sit here and really sort of
like manage it and you're wanting to
make sure everything's safe, you know,
maybe start off like this so you can
just understand, oh, okay, it's asking
me if it can run this command or it's
asking me if it can open up my browser
and then you just get familiar with what
it looks like for Codeex to actually run
that agentic loop. You could also go on
approveof for me. So it's only going to
ask you if actions are detected as
unsafe like maybe deletes or maybe
certain sorts of like API calls or
things like that. So that's how these
permissions work. And if you really want
to get granular about, oh, I want to
like make sure these certain actions
never happen, you can ask Codex about
that and it can work things into those
config files like we talked about
earlier with the codeex that it can
certainly like block things out. But now
let's move on to number 11, which I
think is my favorite one, which is
skills. Skills are so so important.
They're basically reusable workflows.
They're recipes that let you do
something once and then teach Codex how
to do it the same way every single time.
So now you can just run all these
skills. So like I said, a skill is
basically just a recipe. So, let's say
you come in here and you make, you know,
a chocolate chip pancake and you
followed a recipe to make that pancake.
You would basically say, "Okay, if I
ever want to make chocolate chip
pancakes again, I'm going to use this
recipe because I know that I'm going to
get a good result." But let's say that
you burnt these pancakes and you said,
"Okay, well, what I need to do is make a
quick update in this recipe to say, hey,
you know, cook it up 30 seconds less on
each side." And the next time you run
the skill, you basically see, okay, are
these better? Are these good? Do I need
to make any more feedback in here? Or
now, is this skill just the way I like
it? And then your agents are able to use
these skills. So here's an example where
I basically gave it a YouTube video. So
you can see that this is literally just
a local file path of a YouTube video.
And I said that I needed a video
description, timestamps, and a LinkedIn
post. It went ahead and it ran its
agentic loop and it gave me a
description, timestamps, and a LinkedIn
post. And then I said, "Okay, now I need
you to turn this into an X article." And
put the draft into my X as a draft. And
it knew exactly how to do this with a
thumbnail, with a title. It also put
screenshots from my actual video and it
sprinkled them throughout my whole X
article. And this is because it used a
bunch of skills to be able to know how
to do this. So right here, if I asked
it, what skills did you use? It used my
YouTube description skill, my timestamp
skill, my LinkedIn post skill, my ex
article skill, my ex article from video
skill, my format X article skill. It
used all of these skills because I've
taught it how to do something good once.
And then every time I run these skills,
I just give feedback. Hey, that was
good. You know, I liked this, but I
didn't like this. Update the skill. And
now what's cool is you can just invoke
these either with natural language. It
will be smart enough to do it with
natural language, or you can do it as a
slash command. So, I have one in here
that I can call like the audit. And you
can see this will run my audit or I have
one in here called the 3D brain. And
this runs the 3D brain. Man, I think I
planned this out so good. This is going
to bring us on to number 12, which is
agents. So, we talked about codecs and
agents is basically the exact same. It
just holds different things. So, right
here, you can see that the agents holds
your skills and these once again can
either be project level skills or they
can be user scope skills. So, they can
be global skills. So if I come into this
chat right here which is inside of my um
you know Herk 2 project and I go to open
up the files and I go to my agents
folder which is right here we have a
folder called skills and this is a bunch
of skills as you can see. Now if I open
up an actual skill so for example let me
go to my YouTube description skill. This
is an actual skill.md. So once again MD
just means markdown file. So what we
have here is some metadata and this is
what codeex will read to understand okay
do I need to invoke the skill or not.
So, it has the name and it has basically
when to use the skill. And then all the
skill is is just instructions. It's,
hey, for Nate's YouTube descriptions,
keep them short, two to four sentences,
paragraph form, no bullet points, no m
dashes. Here's the process. You read the
video outline. You identify the core
topic. You write a short paragraph. And
that's the skill. It's a very, very
simple prompt. But if I go to my ex
article one, they can also be way more
in-depth. So, this one is way longer.
There's a lot of other rules and a lot
of other criteria. There's way more
steps. There's way more things to do.
And also what's cool is skills can
reference other things. Skills can
reference other skills. They can
reference other agents. They can
reference Python files or context files.
So in this example, this skill
references my voice guidelines like my
LinkedIn style guide as well as my X
article style guide. But that is where
your skills live inside of the agents
folder. And then moving on to number 13.
Here we have plugins. And this is where
a lot of the magic actually happens
because you can super easily come over
here in the Codex desktop app. You can
go to plugins and you can connect a
bunch of things. You can see all the
stuff that I have installed like Alpaca,
Gmail, ClickUp, Clay, Google Drive,
GitHub, Canva, and the list goes on and
on. You can also search for different
plugins. So, let's say you were really
interested in connecting something like,
I don't know, let's see, do they have a
LinkedIn plugin? They have a LinkedIn
plugin where we can find the right
profession. We can grow our business
with ads. We have all these other sorts
of plugins, too. So, if you want to try
to connect your different apps, just
come in here and see if you can connect
them using these plugins. Maybe they
have Composio, they don't have
Composeio, and if they don't have a
plugin here, you can still connect it
using AENV, using an API key. But
plugins are so much easier because you
can just basically sign in once. They've
got ones for creativity, for developer
tools, for business and operations, for
data analytics, communication, and
they're basically always growing this
plug-in library. All right, so that now
brings us on to part four, which is
tools and scale. Okay, we've got five
left here. Number 14, we have the
browser. Now, this is definitely one of
my favorite things about Codeex. If I
open up the tab over here, we can open
up a browser, which is really cool
because I can basically just control
this. So, like I could go to school.com.
And what you'll notice is when I log
into school.com over here, I'm just
going to zoom out a little bit. You can
see right here that I'm already logged
into my school account. So, I could
manage my different communities, which
also means that Codeex can help me
manage my communities from here. Because
when you save these login inside of the
Codeex browser, it then saves them. So,
if you say, "Hey, could you go to that
account and pull the report for me?" or
hey could you go into school and could
you make this post for me it can do it
through the browser if there's not a
plugin or if there's not like an API or
MCP server and the browser use of codeex
and specifically with GBT6 Astra is the
best that I've ever used ever I'll play
a clip right here where I asked it to
basically open up Canva and paint me and
draw me using the tools in there and I
gave it just a picture of me and it was
able to replicate it in a way that I
thought was really really good. So silly
example, but it definitely demonstrates
the vision and the browser use
capability of this agent. All right, so
number 15 we have sites. So if you go
over here to explore and you click on
sites, this is very very cool because it
basically lets you put things out there
onto the cloud. Remember earlier we
talked about local versus cloud. Codex
can build something for you and it can
be a local host but then you say, "Hey,
can you just put that on a site real
quick so that you could have your team
log in or so that you could share it
with, you know, other people and make it
publicly accessible." Like right here,
you can see this London and Paris one is
everyone whoever has this URL could go
ahead and open this up. Whereas this one
is just me. So it would literally have
to be logged into my account in order to
be able to open up this site. And what
else is amazing about that is you can
open up the analytics for the site. So
you can basically host things. You can
connect your own domain and this is
basically going to replace something
like a Verscell or like a I don't know a
Squarespace, wherever you wanted to host
your sites normally. You can now just do
it right here from the Codex desktop app
which is pretty cool. You can also even
connect a database. So on the back end
if you had to store like user login data
or you know permissions or settings or
you know a database of customer records
whatever it is you could actually store
that here too and it's really cool. All
you need to do to actually use a site is
you just basically have to do either say
hey can you turn that into a site or you
could do slash site and then it will
basically know that you can you know
host a site or build a site. So great
touch here from codeex. All right so
number 16 we have sub aents. So, sub
agents are really cool because it lets
you delegate work out to a bunch of
different CEX agents. So, right here in
this main chat, you can see that I'm
talking to GBT6 Astra, which is a
really, really smart and intelligent,
but also expensive model. So, let's say
I wanted to do a bunch of research, but
I didn't want to waste Astra's brain on
that. Or let's say I wanted to do like a
bunch of different testing and just do a
lot of stuff at once. Astra here that
I'm talking to can delegate workout to
tons of sub aents. Hey, I need you to
search through X and search through
YouTube and also dig through my own
comments. So, just find, you know, what
are people talking about right now in
the AI space? Is there any big news or
drama? I don't want you to do this
research though. I want you to basically
just delegate a bunch of sub agents out
to do the work. And I want all of these
sub aents to be using 5.6 Terra as the
model. So, shoot off those agents and
let me know what they find. So, this is
really cool because I can specify that I
want those sub aents, those little like
researchers and workers to use different
models. So right here it's using its
agentic loop and it's going to spin up
these agents. And whenever you see these
little colorful things, these are
different agents that it's spun up. So
right here, this one's called X. And
when I open up X, it is actually this
sub agent working right here. I can
watch this sub agent go through its
agentic loop and I can watch it like
pull in data and everything like that.
So this is the same thing as over here,
but this one is just a different model
and it's not the main session that
you're currently talking to. You can see
we have two others that started working.
We have this one called YouTube Pulse.
And once again, it's going through the
same exact aentic loop. We have this one
called X drama. We have this one called
audience comments. And we can basically
watch all of these work, but we don't
have to manage them because once these
agents are done, the main session here
will say, "Okay, cool. All five are
done. They reported back to me. Here's
what they found." And this is really
good for gathering different
perspectives or researching out a bunch
of things in parallel. And these
intelligent models are really, really
good at delegation. So sub agents are
definitely something that you need to be
using. So, while these sub aents are
fanned out and they're working, let's
move on to number 17, which is scheduled
tasks. Scheduled tasks are awesome
because this basically lets you have
your codecs working autonomously for
you. So, on the lefth hand side, if you
click on scheduled, you can basically
ask codecs to schedule things for you,
reminders, updates, or run full sessions
because all a task basically is is it
injects a prompt into a codec session
like this. So it uses your same local
files, it uses your same skills, it uses
your model, it uses everything, the
agentic loop, it just does it
automatically for you. So in here, you
see that I could create one and I could
set it up manually. I could have it run
locally or I have could have it run on
the cloud. I could also choose what
project to work in. So Herk 2 or, you
know, Hyperframes editor. I can also
choose what chat. So every one of these
routines could be a new chat or it could
be a new chat for this task or it could
be even in an existing thread that we
already have going. And then you can
basically choose when to schedule it. So
it could be daily, it could be hourly,
it could be, you know, weekly, or you
could get it really, really custom in
here. And the cool thing is you can
describe everything in here manually, or
you could basically just ask Codex to
make one for you. So, for example, I
have these like seven or eight different
ones that are running for um trading.
They're literally trading $10,000 of my
real money. And I have this set up as
scheduled task so that they can
basically all work together, talk to
each other, check the market, make
trades, things like that. And of course,
you guessed it, these run in a different
project right here called trading
challenge. And they all run inside of
this challenge thread. You can tell that
this has scheduled tasks in it because
there's a little clock icon next to that
thread. And moving on to the very last
concept we have for today, number 18,
this is voice mode. Now, everything that
you've learned so far, skills, sub
aents, projects, agents, all of this can
be controlled by using your voice to
have a real conversation with codecs.
With your voice, you can manage
different codeex threads. You can
delegate different agents, you can run
skills, you can set up schedule tasks,
you can build sites, you can do anything
here with your voice. And all you have
to do is come down to the bottom left
and click on start new voice chat. So,
forgive me here as I'm awkwardly like
hunching down because my headphones
don't reach far enough. But watch this.
Hey, Codex. So, I need you to help me
out real quick inside of my Herk 2
project. Can you start a new thread to
make a thumbnail? I'm making this
YouTube video about 18 CEX concepts. So,
if you could make me a thumbnail for my
YouTube channel where you see me sitting
at a desk working on a laptop and I'm
pointing to the right and there's like
18 different little AI agents. Um, yeah,
just start start with that. And then
once you have finished that thumbnail,
could you send it to the thread that is
currently working inside of my HERK 2 as
well and it is doing research on YouTube
and X and um looking at my channel and
stuff like that. Could you just send
that thumbnail to that thread?
>> All right, let me check on that. Okay,
I've got your thumbnail brief queued up
with you with the laptop pointing toward
the 18 ages using your existing photos
for reference. And now found your
research thread. So I'll send the
finished thumbnail there. Now, do you
guys see how this is all coming
together? It started a work tree chat.
It was doing the agentic loop. It also
created a goal down here. It literally
created its own goal because it knew
that we had this, you know, task for it
and it started working. And you know,
the voice chat's still going. So, I
don't know what it's going to think of
this, but I just wanted to call that out
because all of what we just talked about
is all coming together because even you
can see over here, it started making
that actual prompt. Like, it shot off
this prompt right here and it started
off this new thread. And now, this is
working in a work tree and it's going to
create that thumbnail for us and then
it's going to send it over into this
actual chat and we'll see that actually
happen. But as you keep navigating, like
you can go to the web and you can go to,
you know, other things and you can keep
this voice working. So as you're just
working on your laptop, it'll show you
what's going on and you can keep talking
to it. And you can also do all this on
your phone as well because of the whole
remote thing, you can use voice mode
when you're on your phone, too. Okay, so
that finished up and you can see what
happens is it actually can send tasks or
messages to each other, right? So, what
happened was this was the original
thread that it created to make the image
and it made this and then it sent it to
this thread and said, "Hey, Nate wanted
me to send this to you. Here it is." So,
with just your voice, I know that was a
very simple example, but you're able to
coordinate a bunch of different codec
threads, manage them, multitask while
you're on the go, while you're flipping
between different apps. Very cool. But
anyways, guys, that is going to do it. I
hope you enjoyed. I hope you learned
something new. But if you want to keep
diving into more stuff with Codex, and
I've made so many videos, I'll tag a
playlist right up here that has just a
bunch of Codeex content. So, hope to see
you guys over there. Thanks for sticking
to the end, and I'll see you in the next
one. Thanks everyone.